Guide to the Lee S. Shulman Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
- PROJECTS, Series 5
  - Cathy Davenport: notes re. lesson planning (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Margaret Scott: notes re. lesson planning (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Carol Wilson: notes re. lesson planning (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Scoring protocols: originals, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - History: Exercise 5 Lesson Planning (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Scoring Guides (1) (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Scoring Guides (2) (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Scoring Guides (3) (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Scoring Guides (4) (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Scoring Guides (5) (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Hilger - Grover - Stein correspondence to Vavrus, April 15, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Hilger - Grover correspondence to Shulman, December 9, 1987 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Grover correspondence to Shulman, 1987 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Lesson Structures: scoring, 1987 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Candidates: Lesson Structures scores, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Candidates: Rating Summary (math) (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Grover: "Developing a Scoring System for Secondary Mathematics," 1987 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Grover: "CT - Scoring System" draft 3, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Grover: "CT - Scoring System: Objectives and Competencies," draft 2, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - "Rationale and Assumptions of Scoring System," draft, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - "Task I: Structuring a Unit," draft, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Grover: "Structuring a Unit," draft, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Grover: "Task 2: Structuring a Lesson," draft, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Grover: "Task 3: Alternative Approaches," draft, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Grover: "Task 4: Evaluating Student Performance," 1987 (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Cover Pages for Technical Reports (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Exercise Summaries (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Original Graphics for Overview Report (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Prototype Report Memos (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Scoring Materials: blank forms (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - Scorer comments (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - Scoring Matierals: miscellaneous materials (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - Scoring: Acknowledgement letters (Box 19, Folder 23)
  - Scorer Training: July 7-8, 1988 (Box 19, Folder 24)
  - Scorer Training: July 18-19, 1988 (Box 19, Folder 25)
  - Scorers: Round One (Box 19, Folder 26)
  - Scorers: Round Two (Box 19, Folder 27)
  - Carnegie Meeting Notes, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 28)
  - Teacher Assessment Project and National Board of Teaching: miscellaneous correspondence, etc, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 29)
  - Press Releases, reports: 1986 (Box 19, Folder 30)
  - Teacher Assessment Project and National Board of Teaching: miscellaneous correspondence, etc, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 31)
  - Teacher Assessment Project and National Board of Teaching: miscellaneous correspondence, etc, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 32)
  - Test Validity, June 23, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 33)
  - Teacher Assessment Project and National Board of Teaching: miscellaneous correspondence, etc, 1988 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Teacher Assessment Project and National Board of Teaching: miscellaneous correspondence, etc, 1988 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - California/Connecticut Liason on New Teacher Assessments, 1988 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Teacher Assessment Project and National Board of Teaching: miscellaneous correspondence, etc, 1989 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Carnegie Corporation Grant, 1990 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Teacher Assessment Project and National Board of Teaching: miscellaneous correspondence, etc, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Carnegie: Ed Haertel, 1986-1988 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - States Consortium: Miscellaneous: 1986-1988 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Carnegie Miscellaneous: Search - Teacher Collaborators, 1987 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Carnegie Miscellaneous: Staff biographical information (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Carnegie Miscellaneous: Press releases (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Carnegie Miscellaneous: Search - Field Test Coordinator (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Carnegie Miscellaneous: Search - Asst. Prof. Project Director (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Steering Committee: List, general, 1987 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Steering Committee: Meeting 1, July 17-18, 1986 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Steering Committee: Meeting 1, July 17-18, 1986 (transcript) (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Steering Committee: Meeting 2, January 28-29, 1987 (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - Steering Committee: Meeting 3, May 27, 1987 (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Steering Committee: correspondence (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - Teacher Advisory Board: correspondence (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Teacher Advisory Board: applicant pool (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Teacher Advisory Board: List, general (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Teacher Advisory Board: Meeting 1, January 24, 1987 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Teacher Advisory Board: Meeting 2, April 4, 1987 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Teacher Education: correspondence (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Carnegie Wisdom of Practice: Lists, general (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Carnegie Wisdom of Practice: consent forms, 1986-1987 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Carnegie Wisdom of Practice: correspondence, miscellaneous (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Carnegie Wisdom of Practice: Information forms (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Carnegie Wisdom of Practice: Math teacher collaborators (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Carnegie Wisdom of Practice: Math teachers interviewed (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Carnegie Wisdom of Practice: Math teachers interviewed and observed (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Carnegie Wisdom of Practice: Principals/Superintendents (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Carnegie Wisdom of Practice: Protocols, math (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Carnegie Wisdom of Practice: Protocols, social studies (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Carnegie Wisdom of Practice: Social Studies teacher collaborators (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Carnegie Wisdom of Practice: Social Studies Teachers interviewed (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - Carnegie Wisdom of Practice: Social Studies Teachers interviewed and observed (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - Carnegie Wisdom of Practice: "Why Wisdom of Practice Research" (Box 21, Folder 20)
  - Carnegie Misc.: correspondence, memos, and miscellaneous (Box 21, Folder 21)
  - Carnegie Misc.: Phase I Proposal, Shulman (Box 21, Folder 22)
  - Carnegie Misc.: 1987/88 - 1988/89 Proposal (Box 21, Folder 23)
  - Carnegie Misc.: correspondence to/from Carnegie Corporation (Box 21, Folder 24)
  - Carnegie Misc.: Sponsored Projects, 1986-1989 (Box 21, Folder 25)
  - Assessment: Consulting firms (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Assessment: Miscellaneous correspondence (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Assessment: On-the-job assessment center (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Assessment: Other countries (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Assessment: Other fields (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Assessment: Other states (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Assessment: Testing houses (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Assessment: Undergraduate aassessment center (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Assessment Technologies Conference (ATC): Agenda, guidelines (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - ATC: Attendents, paid (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - ATC: Attendents, Stanford (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - ATC: Attendents, Steering Committee (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - ATC: Attendents, unpaid (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - ATC: Executive Summary (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - ATC: Handouts from speakers (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - ATC: Lists, general (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - ATC: Notes on tapes, Sofi Aburto (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - ATC: Post-conference thak you letters (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - ATC: Pre-conference thank you letters (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - ATC: Presenters (Box 22, Folder 20)
  - ATC: Rejection letters (Box 22, Folder 21)
  - ATC: Travel, lodging, events and services (Box 22, Folder 22)
  - Expert Panels: History panel correspondence, 1987 (Box 22, Folder 23)
  - Expert Panels: History panel list, general, 1987 (Box 22, Folder 24)
  - Expert Panels: History panel meeting #1: agenda, handouts, etc., 1987 (Box 22, Folder 25)
  - Expert Panels: History panel meeting #1: food, lodging, logistics, 1987 (Box 22, Folder 26)
  - Expert Panels: History panel meeting #1: transcript, February 1987 (Box 22, Folder 27)
  - Expert Panels: History panel meeting #1: transcript, February 1987 (Box 22, Folder 28)
  - Expert Panels: History panel meeting #2: schedule, correspondence, etc., June 1987 (Box 22, Folder 29)
  - Expert Panels: Math panel correspondence, 1986 (Box 22, Folder 30)
  - Expert Panels: Math: list, general (Box 22, Folder 31)
  - Expert Panels: Math meeting, November 1986 (Box 22, Folder 32)
  - Expert Panels: Math panel meeting #1: food, lodging, 1986 (Box 22, Folder 33)
  - Expert Panels: Math panel meeting #1: handouts (Box 22, Folder 34)
  - Expert Panels: Math panel meeting #1: notes (Box 22, Folder 35)
  - Expert Panels: Math panel meeting #2: notes (Box 22, Folder 36)
  - Expert Panels: Mathematical Sciences Education Board (Box 22, Folder 37)
  - Correspondence: Angelo Collins (Box 22, Folder 38)
  - Correspondence: Independent Schools (Box 22, Folder 39)
  - Correspondence: Interested parties (chronological) 1986-1988 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: resumes, 1986 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Vavrus, L. G. (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Wilson; Miscellaneous 1986-1987 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Minorities conference: agenda, misc.1987 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Minorities conference: correspondence (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Minorities conference: handouts (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Minorities conference: participants, lists (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Minorities conference 2: agenda, 1988 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Minorities conference 2: handouts, materials from participants (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Minorities conference 2: lists (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Minorities conference 2: logistics, hotel, food, rooms (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Minorities conference 2: participants, letters, correspondence (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Minorities conference 2: reflections, highlights, etc. (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Minorities consortium: Sharon Nelson-Barber correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Minorities consortium: Mid-year meeting, November 1988 (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - Carnegie Miscellaneous: articles in the news (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Carnegie Miscellaneous: Contacts in Education field (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - Carnegie Miscellaneous: mailing lists (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - TAP Chronology (Preliminary) (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - "An Odyssey of Teacher Assessment: Final Report of the Teacher Assessment Project," Lee Shulman, December 1991 (includes list of Project Publications) (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - "Toward Alternative Assessments of Teaching," Shulman, Haertel, Bird (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - "The BioTAP Story: A Narrative Description of an Exploration," Collins (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - "Report on the Use of Portfolios to Assess Biology Teachers," Bird and King (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - "Assessment Center Exercises for High School Biology Teachers," King (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - "Report on the Rating Procedure Used to Assess Portfolio & Assessment Center Exercises for High School Biology Teachers," Bird (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - "An In-Depth Look at the Student Evaluation Portfolio: Problems and Potential," King, March 1990 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - "An In-Depth Look at the Student Evaluation Interview Exercises: Problems and Potential," King, April 1990 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - BioTAP: Unit Planning and Exercises, B-6 - B-12 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - BioTAP: Unit Planning and Exercises, B-13 - B-19 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - "Thinking about Linking Portfolios with Assessment Center Exercises: Examples from the Teacher Assessment Project," King (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Portfolio Entry Construction Kit for Teaching a Laboratory Lesson (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Portfolio Development Handbook for Teachers of Biology (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Appendix to Portfolio Development Handbook (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Biology Participants Handbook, Assessment Center (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - Biology Examiner's Handbook for the Assessment Center (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - "A Teacher's Portfolio: What is Necessary and Sufficient?" Collins (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - "Novices, Experts, Veterans, and Masters: The Role of Content, Pedagogical Knowledge in Evaluating Teaching," Collins (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - "Social Consequences of Standard Setting in the Professions," Sykes (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - "A Union of Insufficiencies: Strategies for the Teacher Assessment in a Period of Educational Reform," Shulman (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - "National Standards, Local Organization," Bird (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - "Teacher Assessment and Professionalization," Bird (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - "The Schoolteacher's Portfolio: An Essay on Possibilities," Bird (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - "Preparing for the Pedagogical Decathlon…," Wilson (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - "The 100 Statements Project: A Study in the Dynamics of Teacher Assessment," Kerdeman (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - "Use of Assessment Center to Evaluate Teacher Competencies," Byham (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - "Learning to Teach Problematic Instructional Material: Cases from Experienced and Novice Teachers," Barnett (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - "Elementary Literacy Component of the Teacher Assessment Project: Research Program Overview," 1988 [LAP] (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Examiner's Handbook, 1989 [LAP] (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - "The Portfolio and the Teacher as Reflective Practitioner," Onore (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - "Assessing the Teaching of Literacy in the Elementary Grades: Project Overview," Athanases (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - "Evaluating Teacher Knowledge and Skill in Student Assessment through Teacher Portfolios," Wolf (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - "Assessing the Planning and Teaching of Integrated Language Arts in the Elementary Grades," Athanases (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - "Assessing How Elementary Teachers of Literacy Create a Literate Environment," Chin (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - "Assessing Teacher Skills & Knowledge in the Selection and Use of Literature in Elementary Grades," Athanases (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - "Portfolio Development Handbook for Teachers of Elementary Literacy," Vavrus (and excerpts), 1990 revision (Box 25, Folder 19)
  - "Literacy Examiner's Handbook for the Assessment Center," Vavrus (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - "Portfolios Rating Manuals for Teachers," Vavrus et.al. (pp. 1-124) (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - "Portfolios Rating Manuals for Teachers," Vavrus et.al. (pp. 125-226) (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - "Using Teacher Portfolios to Assess Planning, Instruction, and Teacher Reflection in Elementary Language Arts," Athanases (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - "The Schoolteacher's Portfolio: Practical Issues in Design, Implementation, and Evaluation," Wolf (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - "Thinking about Linking Portfolio Entries with Assessment Center Exercises: Examples from TAP," King (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - "Teacher's Views on Performance-Based Assessments," King (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - "Literature Discussions: Teacher Assessment and Classroom Practice," Barton (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - "The Teacher's Written Plan: Its Problems and Potential as an Assessment Tool," Aninao (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - "Some Old Issues Revisited, A New Issue Emerging," Aninao (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - "Issues of Validity and Reliability in Assessment Center Exercises and Portfolios," Haertel (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - "Tables from the History Assessment," Haertel, Jones, Muo-Ying Li (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - "Tables from the Mathematics Assessment," Haertel, Jones, Muo-Ying Li (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - "Tables from the Literacy Assessment," Haertel, Jones, Muo-Ying Li (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - "Tables from the Biology Assessment," Haertel, Jones, Muo-Ying Li (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - "Variations on a Theme: Regional Nuances in the Assessment of Teachers," Nelson-Barber (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - "Thinking Out Loud: Proceedings of the TAP Forum on Equity in Teacher Assessment," Nelson-Barber (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - "Dayton Public Schools/Wright State University Entry Year Teacher Program: A Very Early Formative Report," Berry and Mann (Box 26, Folder 18)
  - "Symposium on Equity Issues in Teacher Assessment," Aburto, Nelson-Barber (Box 26, Folder 19)
  - "Multicultural Context a Key Factor in Teaching," Nelson-Barber and Meier (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - "University of Alaska Fairbanks Cross-Cultural Teacher Education Program," Barnhardt (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - "The Reform Movement and Minority Students in Teacher Education Programs," Barnhardt and Barnhardt (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Portfolio Development: Draft (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - "Preservice Teacher Assessment Project," Gadson (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - "A Minority Preservice Teacher Assessment Project," Ellis and Barber-Nelson (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - K-Base (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - California State Department of Education: grant extension, 6/15/1989 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - 1995 Deleware Curriculum Framework: Science, Mathematics, Social Studies (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - TAP Mathematics Technical Reports: M1-M3 (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - TAP Mathematics Technical Reports: M4 (1988, 1989) (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - TAP Mathematics Technical Reports: M6 (1988, 1989) (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - TAP Mathematics Technical Reports: M7 (1988, 1989) (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - TAP Mathematics Technical Reports: M8 - M9 (1988, 1989) (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - TAP Mathematics Technical Reports: M10 and H8 (1988, 1989) (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - TAP Mathematics Technical Reports: M11-M12 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - TAP History Technical Reports: H1, H3 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - TAP History Technical Reports: H6 (1988, 1989) (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - TAP History Technical Reports: H7 (1988, 1989) (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - TAP: Study Group on Alternative Assessment Methods, Aburto, Haertel (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Portfolio Entry Review and Assessment Center Exercises Rating Manual, 1989 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - "Elementary Literacy Assessment Center Examiner's Handbook," (pp. 1-110) Vavrus, Athanases, Chin, Wolf, and Sugarman, 1989-1990 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Elementary Literacy Assessment Center Examiner's Handbook, (pp. 111-228) Vavrus, Athanases, Chin, Wolf, and Sugarman, 1989-1990 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - "Elementary Literacy Assessment Center Examiner's Handbook," Shulman: notes - AOS exercises (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - "Elementary Literacy Assessment Center Examiner's Handbook," Shulman: CLE exercises - evaluation materials (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - "Elementary Literacy Assessment Center Examiner's Handbook," Shulman: evaluation materials (cont.) (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Portfolio Development Handbook for Teachers of Elementary Literacy, 1988 (L-5) (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Portfolio Development Handbook for Teachers of Elementary Literacy," 1988 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Portfolio Development Handbook for Teachers of Elementary Literacy," 1988 (with corrections) (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - "Field Testing for Elementary Mathematics," Thomas Romberg comments, 1987 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Field Testing for Elementary Mathematics, cover - exercise 4 (with corrections) (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Field Testing for Elementary Mathematics, exercise 5 - general information (with corrections) (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Wisdom of Practice Summary Notebook (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Interviews between Mathematicians and Teachers: Wisdom of Practice (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - "Biology Examiner's Assessment Center Handbook," Shulman copy (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - "Field Testing for High School Social Studies Examiner Materials," Sykes copy, cover - exercise 3 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Field Testing for High School Social Studies Examiner Materials, Sykes copy, exercise 4 - general information (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Teaching Assessment Projects: South Carolina (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Teaching Assessment Projects: North Carolina, South Carolina, Texas (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Teaching Assessment Projects: Georgia (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - First Mock Board (10/30/87); notes; TFL (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - TAP Newsletter: January 1987 - Fall 1989 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - "From Recitation to Discussion: Shaping Classroom Discourse in the Study of Literature," Steven Athanases (Dissertation Proposal Title), May 30, 1989 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - BioTAP: Angelo Collins correspondence, December 1988-April 1989 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - TAP: Project Publications, 1986-1990 (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Report of Phase III of the Teacher Assessment Project, 9/1/89 - 8/31/90 (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - "Problems in the Assessment of Teacher Portfolios of Integrated Language Arts Instruction," Athanases, 1989 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - "A Research Strategy for the Assessing Teachers of Elementary Literacy: The Promise of Performance Portfolios," Vavrus and Calfee, 1988 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - "Portfolios of Elementary Literacy Instruction: Findings from Stanford's Teacher Assessment Project," Vavrus (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - "Notes on an Exploration of Portfolio Procedures for Evaluating High School Biology Teachers," Bird, 1989 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - "Classroom Video Tips for Teachers," Jacobs, 1988 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - "Cultural Bridges to Knowledge: Accounting for 'Cultural Context' in the Education of Teachers," Nelson-Barber (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - "Emerging Elements for a Conceptual Framework for the Teacher Assessment Project," Sykes, 1987 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - "The Biology Component of the Teacher Assessment Project Research Program Overview," Collins, 1988 (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - "BioTAP: A New Approach to Biology Teacher Assessment," Collins, 1989 (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - "Transforming the Assessment of Teachers Notes on a Theory of Assessment for the 21st Century," Collins, 1990 (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - "How to Develop a Portfolio," Collins (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - "Designing Portfolios for the Assessment of Elementary Literacy Teaching: Work in Progress," Wolf, Athenases, Chin, 1988 (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - "A Candidate-Centered Approach to the Assessment of Teaching," Wineburg, 1988 (Box 32, Folder 13)
  - "Portfolio Documentation and Assessment Center Exercises: A Marriage Made for Teacher Assessment," Vavrus, Collins, 1988 (Box 32, Folder 14)
  - "Issues in Evaluating Portfolios of Teaching: Cases from Elementary Literacy and High School Biology," Vavrus, Collins, 1989 (Box 32, Folder 15)
  - BioTAP: General information, 1989-1990 (Box 32, Folder 16)
  - Carnegie Misc.: National Board for Professional Teaching Standards (NBPTS), 1989 (Box 32, Folder 17)
  - UC San Diego Subcontract, 1986-1988 (Box 32, Folder 18)
  - UC Berkeley Subcontract, 1987-1988 (Box 32, Folder 19)
  - Teacher Standards: A Challenge for Teacher Education, Teleconference sponsored by CACTE at CalState, 1987 (Box 32, Folder 20)
  - Task Force on Teaching as a Profession, 1985 (Box 32, Folder 21)
  - Holmes Group: correspondence, articles, 1985 (Box 32, Folder 22)
  - BioTAP Handbook: Portfolio Development for High School Biology Teachers, 1988 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Elementary Literacy Assessment Center Examiner's Handbook, cover- p.52 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Elementary Literacy Assessment Center Examiner's Handbook, p.53 - end (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Literacy Assessment Center Examiner's Handbook: Appendix B,C (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Literacy Assessment Center Examiner's Handbook: Appendix D, E, F (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Candidate K: questionnaires, scoring materials, etc., 1988 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Notes of Candidate K: scoring materials, etc., 1988 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Candidate B: Questionnaires, scoring material, etc., 1988 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Candidate B: Questionnaires, scoring material, etc., 1988 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Office miscellaneous: furniture equipment (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Office miscellaneous: transcribers (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Office miscellaneous: video equipment (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Office miscellaneous: filing system (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - BioTAP: correspondence: thank you letters (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - BioTAP: orientation, September 23, 1988 (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - BioTAP: Development Team Materials (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - BioTAP: Consent Form: teacher participant (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - BioTAP: memos, minutes, etc. 6/1/88 - (Box 34, Folder 11)